<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rohit Kumar</title>
    <link>https://aquatiko.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Rohit Kumar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zn-Hans</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://aquatiko.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What Coala Organization taught me: Reaching beyond the beginners threshold</title>
      <link>https://aquatiko.github.io/blog/2019-05/what-coala-organization-taught-me-reaching-beyond-the-beginners-threshold/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aquatiko.github.io/blog/2019-05/what-coala-organization-taught-me-reaching-beyond-the-beginners-threshold/</guid>
      <description>So, you have finally convinced yourself to enter the realm of Open Source Development. But wait, the initial threshold of getting to speed in this domain is feeling too difficult for you. You are struggling to do your very first contribution in a big Open-Source repository. The huge code-base is too overwhelming and difficult to understand. The issues marked as simple are also too difficult to comprehend. There are just too many things you still don&amp;rsquo;t know. The list of things you are seeing for the first time is growing day by day. It seems it&amp;rsquo;s a bad choice after all?
So my dear open-sorcerer, have some hope. This feeling is mutual with at-least 60% of the people out there. It always starts with a bumpy road but if you can cross that part, believe me, the road ahead is smoother than you can imagine.
I started with OSS on 15th Sept with zero knowledge of this domain, I just knew some of the features of GitHub GUI. My first PR was to NLTK on 22nd Sept and for that whole week, I was struggling to just get my first PR in. The issue tracker and the vast code-base to work on was not intuitive enough to get past that threshold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Initilization: The results day</title>
      <link>https://aquatiko.github.io/blog/2019-05/gsoc-initilization-the-results-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aquatiko.github.io/blog/2019-05/gsoc-initilization-the-results-day/</guid>
      <description>It dosen&amp;rsquo;t seems possible until it&amp;rsquo;s done!! The day 6th of March 2019 will always be remembered when dreams actually came true.
We were having our end semester exams and results were going to be displayed at 11:30 PM according to our time-zone. We had the last exam tomorrow at 4 pm and the pressure of GSoC was intense. I came to my hostel dorm after finishing the 4 pm exam that day and I had to study for the last one. I have submitted two proposals for GSoC, one for JuliaText in JuliaLang and other to JuliaAstro in OpenAstronomy. I have worked equally for both of them, maybe a bit more for JuliaText&amp;rsquo;s NLP one. I had an assurance that one of them might get in as I gave my all for them. Strict personal deadlines, iteration of thoughts and planning the best possible ways to strengthen my proposal.
So, I started studying for the last exam around 7-8pm and at the start, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t feeling the pressure of GSoC that much. And as time passed, minutes seemed like hours and the panic grew stronger. I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait till 11:30 PM. So, I was in a state where I couldn&amp;rsquo;t focus enough to let that thought go away and study for the last exam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Collaboratory: Your PitStop</title>
      <link>https://aquatiko.github.io/blog/2019-04/google-collaboratory-your-pitstop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aquatiko.github.io/blog/2019-04/google-collaboratory-your-pitstop/</guid>
      <description>Are you starting on your deep learning journey and things are processing slow!! Or you are already on one and don’t want to buy costly computers for your deep learning endeavors or the cloud computation resources like AWS ,Azure or GCP seems too complicated? Well, Google’s collaboratory is pretty easy and handy tool which will get you started right away!!
So what is Google’s Collaboratory? It is a free cloud based service by Google for developers to experiment with their snippets of python codes. It is a Jupyter notebook type interface which you can use just as your standard python compiler but with more features. Also on top of that it provides you a free Tesla K80 GPU for a run-time of 12hours and after that you only have to re-connect with the service again with a single click!! So in short, unless you have a huge task which would take huge resources and time, you can use Google collab for a faster runtime.
Getting Started Head to your google drive-&amp;gt; click on “New(+)” sign -&amp;gt; click on “More” -&amp;gt; click on “Connect more apps”-&amp;gt; search “collaboratory” and add it. (One time process) You can create a new notebook(compiler) by-&amp;gt; click on “New(+)” sign -&amp;gt; click on “more” -&amp;gt; click on “collaboratory”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I started Open-Source</title>
      <link>https://aquatiko.github.io/blog/2019-04/why-i-started-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aquatiko.github.io/blog/2019-04/why-i-started-open-source/</guid>
      <description>After more than 6 months into this, this question almost seems silly to me&amp;hellip; I remember the first week of September 2018, I was desperate to find just a single good enough reason for convincing me to contribute to the Open-Source community. I wanted to participate in GSoC but the idea of spending my own personal time into someone else project was not convincing me. Even after this, something changed and convinced me to do so. I hope by the end of it, you too will be convinced or at least give it a thought!!
Back in those days, I was exploring the depths of Deep Learning. My interest was divided among the most exciting domains popular those days. But somehow NLP was the top one. It was fascinating and enough to keep me there. The same year, two of my seniors became the first batch to crack GSoC from my college. I can say, it totally sparked hope in others.
I remember the day 15th September, I decided I too want it and started preparing for it. I know it was way too early to aim for it, but at that time I was familiar only with some markdown syntax and basic GitHub interface.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>