<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GSoC on Rohit Kumar</title>
    <link>https://aquatiko.github.io/tags/gsoc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GSoC on Rohit Kumar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zn-Hans</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://aquatiko.github.io/tags/gsoc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Initilization: The results day</title>
      <link>https://aquatiko.github.io/blog/2019-05/gsoc-initilization-the-results-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aquatiko.github.io/blog/2019-05/gsoc-initilization-the-results-day/</guid>
      <description>It dosen&amp;rsquo;t seems possible until it&amp;rsquo;s done!! The day 6th of March 2019 will always be remembered when dreams actually came true.
We were having our end semester exams and results were going to be displayed at 11:30 PM according to our time-zone. We had the last exam tomorrow at 4 pm and the pressure of GSoC was intense. I came to my hostel dorm after finishing the 4 pm exam that day and I had to study for the last one. I have submitted two proposals for GSoC, one for JuliaText in JuliaLang and other to JuliaAstro in OpenAstronomy. I have worked equally for both of them, maybe a bit more for JuliaText&amp;rsquo;s NLP one. I had an assurance that one of them might get in as I gave my all for them. Strict personal deadlines, iteration of thoughts and planning the best possible ways to strengthen my proposal.
So, I started studying for the last exam around 7-8pm and at the start, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t feeling the pressure of GSoC that much. And as time passed, minutes seemed like hours and the panic grew stronger. I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait till 11:30 PM. So, I was in a state where I couldn&amp;rsquo;t focus enough to let that thought go away and study for the last exam.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>