<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GSoC on Rohit Kumar</title>
    <link>https://aquatiko.github.io/tags/gsoc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GSoC on Rohit Kumar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zn-Hans</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://aquatiko.github.io/tags/gsoc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2 weeks into GSoC</title>
      <link>https://aquatiko.github.io/blog/2019-06/2-weeks-into-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aquatiko.github.io/blog/2019-06/2-weeks-into-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>I had a feeling in the community bonding period that something will mess up at the start of the coding period as I had the toughest part lined at the start. The same did happen&amp;hellip; At the start, I had two weeks for porting reproject from Astropy. In short what it does is, it align two different astronomical images into a single frame of reference. While capturing an astronomical image, different conditions(like the position of the sky) affects the image captured. Thus, two images of the same region of interest will not be exactly similar when taken under different conditions. It may require to rotate, translate or interpolate them to get the result.
So where the difficulty arises for me? Astropy is a very mature library but support for Astronomy in Julia is still growing. This means that I can&amp;rsquo;t port line by line, I need to be creative. Plus the utility functions which the python version of reproject calls was not present in Julia. So at a basic level, it meant I had to port every other function in Julia or get a workaround using the existing things. So a project part which seemed within bounds at the beginning started growing exponentially and I haven&amp;rsquo;t planned this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Initilization: The results day</title>
      <link>https://aquatiko.github.io/blog/2019-05/gsoc-initilization-the-results-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aquatiko.github.io/blog/2019-05/gsoc-initilization-the-results-day/</guid>
      <description>It dosen&amp;rsquo;t seems possible until it&amp;rsquo;s done!! The day 6th of March 2019 will always be remembered when dreams actually came true.
We were having our end semester exams and results were going to be displayed at 11:30 PM according to our time-zone. We had the last exam tomorrow at 4 pm and the pressure of GSoC was intense. I came to my hostel dorm after finishing the 4 pm exam that day and I had to study for the last one. I have submitted two proposals for GSoC, one for JuliaText in JuliaLang and other to JuliaAstro in OpenAstronomy. I have worked equally for both of them, maybe a bit more for JuliaText&amp;rsquo;s NLP one. I had an assurance that one of them might get in as I gave my all for them. Strict personal deadlines, iteration of thoughts and planning the best possible ways to strengthen my proposal.
So, I started studying for the last exam around 7-8pm and at the start, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t feeling the pressure of GSoC that much. And as time passed, minutes seemed like hours and the panic grew stronger. I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait till 11:30 PM. So, I was in a state where I couldn&amp;rsquo;t focus enough to let that thought go away and study for the last exam.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>